<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Logan Williams</title>
    <link>http://subject.space/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Logan Williams</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://subject.space/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Stamen: 12 Sunsets</title>
      <link>http://subject.space/projects/stamen-12-sunsets/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://subject.space/projects/stamen-12-sunsets/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>East Bay Live</title>
      <link>http://subject.space/projects/east-bay-live/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://subject.space/projects/east-bay-live/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stamen: UCSF Health Atlas</title>
      <link>http://subject.space/projects/health-atlas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://subject.space/projects/health-atlas/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>glenecho.stream</title>
      <link>http://subject.space/projects/glenecho-stream/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://subject.space/projects/glenecho-stream/</guid>
      <description>Reflections, data, and observations of an urban creek. AIR HUMIDITY QUALITY WATER DEPTH TURBIDITY &#34;With ongoing environmental degradation at local, regional, and global scales, people&#39;s accepted thresholds for environmental conditions are continually being lowered. In the absence of past information or experience with historical conditions, members of each new generation accept the situation in which they were raised as being normal.&#34; Soga, M. and Gaston, K. &#34;Shifting baseline syndrome: causes, consequences, and implications,&#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carbon footprint modeling maps</title>
      <link>http://subject.space/projects/cool-climate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://subject.space/projects/cool-climate/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Points West</title>
      <link>http://subject.space/projects/selected-photography/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://subject.space/projects/selected-photography/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stamen: Art Processors</title>
      <link>http://subject.space/projects/mona/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://subject.space/projects/mona/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stamen: Google Cloud Storage</title>
      <link>http://subject.space/projects/google-cloud-storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://subject.space/projects/google-cloud-storage/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fogust</title>
      <link>http://subject.space/projects/fogust/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://subject.space/projects/fogust/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conceptquest</title>
      <link>http://subject.space/projects/conceptquest/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://subject.space/projects/conceptquest/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>59th St. Bridge Song</title>
      <link>http://subject.space/projects/fake-park-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://subject.space/projects/fake-park-game/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Isometric Spacelapse</title>
      <link>http://subject.space/projects/isometric-spacelapse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://subject.space/projects/isometric-spacelapse/</guid>
      <description>By transposing the axes of time and image-space position, unusual aerial viewpoints can be generated. In these videos, all rays intersect the horizontal plane at the same angle and all objects are rendered at the same scale.
With this isometric view, everything is granted equal importance and nothing can be diminished to the background. Hills stand next to buildings, and the foreground, so often human, is forced to reckon with with the scale of its setting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poet is used for poems</title>
      <link>http://subject.space/projects/concept-net-poet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://subject.space/projects/concept-net-poet/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vignette</title>
      <link>http://subject.space/projects/vignette/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://subject.space/projects/vignette/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forty Million Daggers!</title>
      <link>http://subject.space/projects/interactive-mojave/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://subject.space/projects/interactive-mojave/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking In New Directions With Google Street View</title>
      <link>http://subject.space/projects/google-street-view/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://subject.space/projects/google-street-view/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fog Today</title>
      <link>http://subject.space/projects/fog-today/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://subject.space/projects/fog-today/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No-tifier</title>
      <link>http://subject.space/projects/no-tifier/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://subject.space/projects/no-tifier/</guid>
      <description>For the Stupid Hackathon 2017, I made a portable wooden rectangle. Every few minutes, it buzzes briefly to deliver a notification. By carrying it in your pocket, you can be notified wherever you are, no matter what you are doing. The medium is the massage.
You can make one yourself! I used an AVR microcontroller and a scavenged cell phone buzzer driven with a MOSFET. The source code is stupid-hackathon-simple.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Caption Obscura</title>
      <link>http://subject.space/projects/caption-obscura/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://subject.space/projects/caption-obscura/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>As Though I Were There</title>
      <link>http://subject.space/projects/a-poem-made-by-walking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://subject.space/projects/a-poem-made-by-walking/</guid>
      <description>About the poem. If a landmark unrecognized does not exist, a non-existent landmark recognized becomes one. Cross the sidewalk and crest the ridgeline. Continue straight, past the library and through the marsh thistles. Follow the stream down the street. Knock on the door and collapse on the summit.
What topographic ritual summons city from chaparral? Where is the boundary between psychogeography and psychogeographical break?
The poem:
&amp;lt;?xml version=&amp;#34;1.0&amp;#34; encoding=&amp;#34;UTF-8&amp;#34;?&amp;gt; &amp;lt;gpx version=&amp;#34;1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thermografree</title>
      <link>http://subject.space/projects/thermografree/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://subject.space/projects/thermografree/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computational photography</title>
      <link>http://subject.space/projects/computational-photography/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://subject.space/projects/computational-photography/</guid>
      <description>Two attempts to reproduce interesting results from computational photography papers.
Phase based motion amplification From Phase-Based Motion Amplification, by Neal Wadhwa, Michael Rubinstein, Fr&amp;eacute;do Durand, and William T. Freeman.
One of the most impressive results from the original paper, the motion of a sleeping baby&#39;s breath amplified. There are some small likely aliasing-related artifacts visible in my version.
Your browser does not support the video tag. Amplified atmospheric light bending from the heat of a stove burner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phase-based frame interpolation</title>
      <link>http://subject.space/projects/phase-frame-interpolation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://subject.space/projects/phase-frame-interpolation/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hokusai backpack</title>
      <link>http://subject.space/projects/hokusai-backpack/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://subject.space/projects/hokusai-backpack/</guid>
      <description>A handmade backpack with custom dyed fabric based on Hokusai&amp;rsquo;s Kirifuri Waterfall at Kurokami Mountain in Shimotsuke.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wears the Territory</title>
      <link>http://subject.space/projects/wears-the-territory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://subject.space/projects/wears-the-territory/</guid>
      <description> Chagrin, Ohio. Cotton and silk. 200 by 1000 stitches. Cambridge and Boston, Massachusetts. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>San Francisco language dot maps</title>
      <link>http://subject.space/projects/san-francisco-language-maps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://subject.space/projects/san-francisco-language-maps/</guid>
      <description>San Francisco is one of the most multilingual places that I have ever lived. I was curious about who spoke what, and where, so I made some maps in the style of The Racial Dot Map to try to show this data. I also wanted to avoid the rendering issues that The Racial Dot Map has, where certain classes of dots are always drawn on top of other classes of dots - in these maps, the rendering order of each dot is randomized.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boundary Conditions</title>
      <link>http://subject.space/projects/boundary-conditions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://subject.space/projects/boundary-conditions/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optical Coherence Tomography</title>
      <link>http://subject.space/projects/oct-thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://subject.space/projects/oct-thesis/</guid>
      <description>For its importance to human sensation, there is surprisingly little known about the mechanics of motion within the ear. Part of the reason for this is the extremely tiny magnitude of motions within the ear &amp;mdash; a sound at the threshold of human hearing creates a vibration on the eardrum the size of a hydrogen atom. From October 2012 until June 2014, I worked with Professor Denny Freeman and his laboratory at RLE on a new fiber optic apparatus for imaging this motion within the ear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General Abstract Nonsense</title>
      <link>http://subject.space/projects/general-abstract-nonsense/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://subject.space/projects/general-abstract-nonsense/</guid>
      <description>Briefly, my previously low-maintenance, music-based radio show (on the one and only WMBR Cambridge 88.1 FM) became a project about musically-integrated story sharing. While most of these shows have disappeared into the ether like some a frequency-modulated sand mandala, I recently discovered a handful on an personal digital archeaology excavation.
April 21, 2014 Listen.
I&#39;m quite proud of all of the track looping on this show, I think it mostly worked very well The Bonobo track here was purely Joe Frank inspired.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transdomain Feedback</title>
      <link>http://subject.space/projects/transdomain-feedback/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://subject.space/projects/transdomain-feedback/</guid>
      <description>A project in Max/MSP for Music Hack Day Boston with Drew Shapiro.
Feedback and control loops frequently cross multiple domains &amp;mdash; mechanical and electrical, discrete and continuous, and software and hardware. When used as an artistic device however, this is less common. The feedback is frequently electrical and acoustic, but rarely is video introduced into the loop. For this project, we explored the artistic effects of a feedback loop that involved all of these elements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linear lens arrays</title>
      <link>http://subject.space/projects/linear-lens-array/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://subject.space/projects/linear-lens-array/</guid>
      <description>N.B. This project was inspired by, extends, and makes use of some Javascript written by my friend, Joshua Horowitz.
A conventional camera focuses all light rays emitted from an object to the same point in the image. In contrast, a lightfield image contains both the location and angle of incident light rays. Much has been written about light field imaging, but to introduce this project, it suffices to explain that it is conventionally accomplished by capturing many images from different perspecives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miscellaneous academic projects</title>
      <link>http://subject.space/projects/academic-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://subject.space/projects/academic-projects/</guid>
      <description>Recursive Augmented Reality Image Processing System 6.111 (FPGA Laboratory) final project, with Jos&amp;eacute; Cruz Serral&amp;eacute;s. Abstract: We have implemented an augmented reality system that can overlay a digital image on a video stream of a real world environment. We read NTSC video data from a video camera and store it in external ZBT memory. A picture frame with colored markers on the corners is held in front of the camera. We then perform chroma-based object recognition to locate the coordinates of the corners.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protei</title>
      <link>http://subject.space/projects/protei/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://subject.space/projects/protei/</guid>
      <description>Protei was an open source sailboat developed with a diverse team of artists and engineers at the V2_ Institute for the Unstable Media. After a month-long collaborative rapid prototypign and design process, this Protei prototype was developed with a unique flexible hull and a novel actuator design, with the intent of tugging a long, oil absorbent tail through small oil spills. I was also personally responsible for developing system firmware, motor control, and sensor feedback.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Squarecave</title>
      <link>http://subject.space/projects/squarecave/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://subject.space/projects/squarecave/</guid>
      <description>In 2009, I built the Squarecave, an analog synthesizer and sequencer. It uses digital CMOS ICs to generate a sequence of oscillations of varying pitch and volume, and then pipes the result through analog filters (lo-pass, hi-pass, band-pass). If I built this again now, there are so many things that I would change, but I still think it sounds great &amp;mdash; maybe someday, I&#39;ll build version 2. (It might even follow a conventional tuning system!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pair Garments</title>
      <link>http://subject.space/projects/pair-garments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://subject.space/projects/pair-garments/</guid>
      <description>The extra-long-sleeved twonic. A product of the San Francisco Stupid Shit No One Needs and Terrible Ideas Hackathon, of which I was a co-organizer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I Ate</title>
      <link>http://subject.space/projects/what-i-ate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://subject.space/projects/what-i-ate/</guid>
      <description>The room is filled with ancient dates,
Where I&#39;ve been and what I ate.
Before I&#39;m asked to throw them out,
I play with every little doubt. An attempt at tracking correlation between geography and happiness. Q: So, how is the happiness variable plotted?
A: It isn&#39;t.
Q: Isn&#39;t happiness an important part of correlating happiness and location? Why was it excluded?
A: It was difficult to collect enough data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
